Danielle Ussery

Full Stack Web Developer / Graphic Designer

Whittier, CA 90601

revelationdesigner@gmail.com

+1 310 908 3989

Motivated Designer and Full Stack Developer with 9 years of design experience and 4 years of development experience creating custom graphic components and web pages with the use of Adobe software, React, and MySQL databases. Strong creative and analytical skills. Adept in various coding languages and debugging. Background in MERN development style and user-centered conceptualization.

Web Portfolio: https://portfolium.com/danielleussery/portfolio

Graphic Portfolio: https://www.revelationdesigns.net

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Graphic Artist

Ultra Pro International LLC - Commerce, CA October 2018 to Present

- Driving the creative direction of campaigns, with an understanding of typography, layout, and art direction
- · Producing print, packaging, advertising, point-of-purchase, and digital graphics
- Reviewing and proofing design materials with multiple vendors
- Liaising effectively with clients and other team members
- Artwork sublimation with a high aptitude for color theory
- Meeting deadlines in high-pressure environment while seeing projects through from inception to production
- Maintaining and improving design standards with the willingness to listen to feedback and use it to improve

Graphic/Web Designer

Glory Bound Missionary Baptist Church - Long Beach, CA September 2014 to November 2018

- Created weekly programs for services
- Managed the upkeep of the church website
- Created event posters and flyer
- Collaborated with the video department to upload recorded content to the site

Design Manager - Business Development

Brandable - Los Angeles, CA January 2018 to July 2018

- Conceptualized and built brand identities based on influencer's needs
- Collaborated with marketing and creative teams to create eye-catching designs and engaging copy

- · Adjusted designs based on feedback from clients, buyers, engineers, and consumer safety groups
- Maintained and improved design standards with the willingness to listen to feedback and use it to improve
- Created marketing materials including sales decks, social media graphics, photos, and videos
- Developed eye-catching, cost-effective and safe packaging for products
- Point of sale (POS) displays
- Retouched product and lifestyle photos
- Project Management stayed in touch with vendors, printing companies, & developers for all projects given
- Technical: HTML, copywriting and editing, package die lines, and product renderings

Production Design Intern

Paper Decor More - Los Angeles, CA August 2016 to April 2018

- · Designed marketing material
- Created ideas for original craft classes
- Designed greeting and event cards

Graphic Designer

2020AVE - Los Angeles, CA

February 2017 to September 2017

- Designed email marketing campaigns and website page banners.
- Maintained data for all email campaigns and delivered analyzed data presentations weekly.
- Maintained database of marketing contacts by segmenting the database by various demographics and psychographics.
- Updated site banners along with page and product links
- Use of Software: Klaviyo, Shopify, Tawk, Google Analytics, and Adobe CS6 programs (Photoshop, Illustrator, Media Encoder, After Effects, Atom)
- Technical: HTML, Split A/B Testing, Copywriting, and Marketing Strategies

Graphic Designer

Ohzone

October 2016 to August 2017

- Mocked up logo designs for a start up company
- Created UI buttons and app icons
- Provided user testing opinions to assist user functionality
- Created low fidelity & high fidelity UI wireframes with page design options

Contract Graphic Designer

Bleu Brand Development - Santa Monica, CA December 2016 to January 2017

- Designed print ready product labels
- Created clientele food truck design
- Use of Software: Photoshop, Illustrator, Media Encoder, After Effects, InDesign

Retail Associate

Macy's - Culver City, CA May 2016 to January 2017 • Organized and tidied the stands in the sales floor

.

- · Maintained clean fitting rooms
- Knowledgeable of items we sold and the best deals in multiple departments
- Assisted customers with questions on sizes and fits of clothing

Retail Sales Consultant: Print Services

Office Depot - Culver City, CA March 2015 to March 2016

- Responsible for completing print service orders correctly and in a timely fashion
- Built lasting customer and associate relationships
- Operated printing equipment: color and b&w printers, laser printers, laminating machines, and binding machines (glue, spiral and comb)
- Use of Software: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Education

Associate Degree in Advanced Full Stack Web Development in Web Development

Bryan University - Tempe, AZ November 2021 to Present

Full Stack Web Development Certificate in Web Development

Bryan University - Tempe, AZ

November 2020 to November 2021

Bachelor of Science in Graphic & Web Design

The Art Institute of California-Argosy University Los Angeles - Santa Monica, CA July 2015 to December 2016

Associate of Science in Graphic Design

Art Institute of California-Argosy University Los Angeles - Santa Monica, CA August 2012 to June 2015

Skills

- Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Dreamweaver, Bridge and Acrobat (9 years)
- After Effects (Motion Graphics) (3 years)
- Word, Exel, PowerPoint (10+ years)
- CSS3, HTML 5 (9 years)
- Utilizes networking and organizational skills, has a sense of color, works collaboratively with others, and great multitask abilities. (5 years)
- Business Development (4 years)
- Acrobat (9 years)
- Dreamweaver (4 years)
- Typography (9 years)

- Graphic Design (9 years)
- Print Production (5 years)
- Motion Graphics (2 years)
- Time Management (9 years)
- Adobe InDesign (9 years)
- Packaging (7 years)
- Adobe Photoshop (9 years)
- Adobe Illustrator (9 years)
- Data Entry (6 years)
- User Interface (UI)
- Copywriting (2 years)
- JavaScript (2 years)
- Email Marketing (2 years)
- Branding (9 years)
- Front-end development (4 years)
- PostgreSQL (Less than 1 year)
- MySQL (Less than 1 year)
- MongoDB (Less than 1 year)
- Mongoose (Less than 1 year)
- Docker (Less than 1 year)
- Apache (Less than 1 year)
- JSON (Less than 1 year)
- DOM (Less than 1 year)
- Express.js (Less than 1 year)
- React (1 year)
- Node.js (Less than 1 year)
- Bootstrap
- APIs
- GitHub
- Git
- Adobe XD
- InVision
- Back-end development
- Test-driven development
- SCSS
- SQL
- Figma
- Art direction
- · Logo design
- HTML5

- Adobe Creative Suite
- Figma
- Editing
- · Web design
- · Responsive web design
- · Graphic design
- Color theory

Links

http://www.revelationdesigns.net/

https://portfolium.com/danielleussery/portfolio

Awards

Best Of Quarter

October 2012

I was awarded Best of Quarter for Type 1, Form and Space and Concept Design between 2012 and 2014.

Dean's Honor Roll

September 2015

Presented with the Dean's Honor Roll certificate for acquiring a GPA of a 3.85.

Best of Quarter

November 2016

I was awarded Best of Quarter in Design Team 2 for the project Santa Monica's New Heroes Celebration.

Oustanding Achievement Award

December 2016

Was awarded the Outstanding Achievement Award for my graduate portfolio.

Assessments

Graphic design — Proficient

October 2019

Using graphic design techniques and producing visual media to communicate concepts.

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

Groups

AIGA

March 2014 to Present

I was the Vice President of the chapter at my campus March 2015 - May 2016 I was the Treasurer from Jan 2015 - March 2015

Alpha Beta Gamma

April 2014 to Present

I am apart of the Alpha Beta Gamma business honor society chapter at my campus.

I was the Lead Designer over a group of four from June 2015 - January 2016. I along with 3 other members designed e-mail flyers and posters.

I was also the Secretary from Jan 2015 - June 2015